WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
His lordship is going to America.
What are you talking about?
A telegram has just arrived.
He's leaving today. Something's
happened to her ladyship's brother.
So, you mean you have to go, too?
I can't leave Anna, Mrs Hughes.
Not now.
How can she put me in this position?
It's not fair!
I agree.
But, why does your mother need me?
"Robert must be there." Why?
My being there won't
make a difference.
They obviously feel it will.
Maybe they don't want the Committee
to think Harold's a wildcat driller.
An earl as a brother-in-law
will make him respectable?
They seem to believe so.
I know plenty of relatives of
English earls who belong in gaol!
I suppose we've made the decision.
- I can't stop his lordship from going.
- Of course not.
But, I wonder if it's necessary
for Mr Bates to go with him.
It'll be very hard for Anna
to lose his support at this time.
Mrs Hughes,
I hope we are good employers,
but even we expect
to get what we pay for.
Bates is in this house
as his lordship's valet.
I know that, m'lady,
but this is a special circumstance.
Why, particularly?
It's not my secret to tell.
If you wish to enlist my help,
I must know the facts.
I won't go.
I see, so you'll leave
his lordship in the lurch,
and probably lose your job,
and all this to help me?
Go home and pack.
You are asking me
to travel without a valet?
I'm asking you not to take Bates.
You do know the Americans
have a correct uniform
for practically every
activity known to man?
Thomas was your valet the whole time
Bates was in prison.
He knows how you like things done.
Suppose he doesn't want to go?
Why wouldn't he? It's an adventure.
All those handsome stewards
strutting down the boat deck.
Don't be vulgar.
What do you know of such matters?
I've been married.
I know everything.
But if you could just explain
why Bates can't come?
I can't explain it.
If I could, you would agree with me.
I found this for the shoes, m'lord.
I'm afraid it seems you won't
be coming with me, Bates.
Thomas has been selected
as your deputy.
What?
Lady Mary persuaded me
you are more needed here,
though why I couldn't tell you.
I'd better get on.
Your grandmother will arrive shortly.
What have they told you?
That Anna was...
..'attacked' by some ruffian
who'd broken in.
While I sat upstairs,
enjoying the music.
It's not your fault, Bates.
It wasn't hers, but it wasn't yours.
Thank you.
I thought I'd come
to wish Lord Grantham
good luck on his journey.
He's upstairs getting ready, m'lady.
Everyone else is in the library.
Oh, Rose, my dear...
I wonder, I wonder if I might
please have a glass of water?
Thank you.
Judging how things are
going, he can manage very well.
Oh? Are we disturbing the conclave?
We're just discussing the pigs.
Ah, the arrival of the pigs
and the departure of their master.
It's sad Lord Grantham
has to miss it.
Are the pigs a good idea, Mr Blake?
It's a good idea for estates
to maximise and diversify.
The question is whether or not
Lord Grantham and Lady Mary
fully appreciate what
they're taking on.
Oh? You ask as if the answer were no.
Mr Blake is not under Mary's spell.
Oh?
Mrs Crawley.
Morning.
Good morning.
Your water, m'lady.
Thank you, Carson.
Are you feeling hot? I am.
I've just walked up
from the village.
I am a bit hot, but I didn't walk.
I envy you.
Well, I'm not sorry. I can say that.
How do you know you'll get a ship?
There's always empty cabins.
Sure we'll find something.
Oh, I wish it were me.
Wouldn't you miss Ivy?
Nothing's gonna come of that.
It were a waste of money and effort.
I'm sure something's
around the corner.
I wish it'd get a move on
or I might do something stupid.
Ha! Well, when I get back,
I want to find you happy and healthy
and courting a girl
from the village.
Come on, let's go up.
You can wish me luck.
Darling, I do think your going to
rescue my hopeless brother
is an act of real love,
and I cherish you for it.
That'll keep me warm
as I cross the raging seas.
Good. Now, kiss me.
Lady Grantham says we can stay
'til we're done.
But, it'll be a few weeks more.
I hope you don't mind.
Not if you make yourselves useful.
We will.
Try to be strong, my darling.
I will.
Gregson must be out there somewhere.
I wish you'd let me send a detective.
There's no point.
His firm's already done all that
to no avail.
If there's anything
you want us to do,
Mama will give you whatever you need.
Goodbye, Mama.
Goodbye, my dear.
Try not to let those Yankees
drive you mad.
Mary? Why so preoccupied?
Am I? I'm afraid my mind
is on other things.
Anyway, goodbye, Papa,
and please try to enjoy yourself.
Good luck with the pigs.
Rose, I leave you in charge of fun.
Mission understood, Captain.
Goodbye, Isobel.
Bye, Tom.
Look after all my womenfolk,
including Isis.
Especially Isis.
I'll try my best.
Goodbye, Miss Baxter. I look forward
to a full report when I get back.
Why am I going instead of Mr Bates?
I don't know.
No, but that's what
you're going to find out.
Oh... Well, that's a relief.
Is it?
Yes, I'm... I'm feeling rather ill.
I wanted him away before I keel over.
I am sorry. Would you like me
to come back with you?
That is the very last thing
I would want.
Oh, Carson, can I have a car please,
to take me home?
Certainly, your ladyship...
Yes, now.
Thank you for seeing him off.
Evelyn wanted to.
But, now we must go
or we'll be late.
Is it just lack of money,
why these places are all failing?
Usually. But, why is that?
Because so few owners make the most
of what an estate has to offer.
So few think about income.
So few are ready to
adjust their way of life.
You have to understand
what these people are used to.
No. They have to get used to
something different.
They think nothing needs to change.
That God will be upset
if the old order is overturned.
And you don't think He will be?
No.
To farm an estate is hard work,
and never more than now.
The owners must face up to that,
or they don't deserve
to keep what they have.
You look very intense.
Mr Blake was saying he finds
people like you and me infuriating.
I should point out...
We must get going or we'll be late.
It's nice of you to drive me home.
I'm meeting the new pig man.
I do worry about your life away
from the estate. Is there any?
Huh, I've no time.
What happened
to your politics?
They vanished. Along with that
silly chauffeur chap named Branson.
I don't believe that.
I gather the MP, John Ward,
is coming to speak in Ripon tomorrow
at the Town Hall.
I could get tickets.
I don't think so.
I'm not a fan of the Coalition,
as it is.
He's only here because Lloyd George
thinks an election's coming.
Well, I doubt he has long, poor dear.
But, I don't think
you're being fair to Mr Ward.
Let's go. What do you say?
I'd say you better be nice to me,
or I'll tell old Lady Grantham you
called Lloyd George "poor dear."
Would you mind
if I went up to London tomorrow?
Is there news of Mr Gregson?
Well, they've pieced together
a little more.
He arrived in Munich
and signed into his hotel.
Then, that evening,
he went out and never came back.
But, it doesn't make any sense.
What was his reason for being there?
To see the castles of King Ludwig.
But darling, surely if he was
attacked or set upon,
they would have found him long ago?
Oh, my dearest one, come here.
I don't ask you not to worry,
only not quite to give up hope.
Of course you must go up to London.
It would do you good.
Mama, can I ask you something?
You don't think I'm bad, do you?
You can be a bit sharp-tongued
every now and then!
But, bad? No.
Sometimes I have bad feelings.
We all have bad feelings.
It's ACTING on them
that makes you bad.
I've had a letter from Alfred.
What's he got to say for himself?
He's doing well.
Some French chap with a name
I can't pronounce,
seems to have taken a shine to him.
I don't think we need praise
from the French quite yet.
Does he mention us?
Er, his father's ill
so he's coming up to visit.
He hopes to look in on his way home
to see us all.
Really?
Why should you care?
She thinks it'd be nice to see him,
Daisy, and so it would be.
Rose? What is it?
I saw Edith on the stairs. She says
she's going to London tomorrow.
So, I wondered if I could go, too.
Rose, in a few months you'll have
been presented, you'll be out.
Everything will be possible.
You said most girls of my age
would already be presented.
Why do you want to go?
Just to see some old friends
you'd approve of madly.
Edith's so worried about Mr Gregson.
Maybe I could cheer her up.
Cousin Robert did leave me
in charge of fun!
Why is he always so superior?
He's frustrated by all the families
who are giving in.
The axe falls
and they do nothing to fight back.
But if they can't afford to go on?
They could if they'd take a new
approach to their inheritance,
instead of watching it being
carted away in boxes to be sold.
He can't think we're doing that.
Well, no.
But, he doubts you'd fight
if it came to it.
Hmm.
He says you're aloof.
Aloof?
Well, I hope you've stuck up for me.
Of course I did, but, well...
Go on.
Charles thinks I'm blind
where you're concerned.
We should go in.
Has anyone told Mr Carson
that tea's ready?
There was a telegram earlier.
He took it up to her ladyship.
That means they've got the boat.
What a bonus for Mr Barrow.
A trip to America out of the blue.
Huh! I wouldn't fancy it,
all steaks and ketchup
and 'hail fellow, well met'.
What do you know about it?
I go to the pictures too, you know!
His lordship has secured passage
on the Cameronia.
They sail tomorrow and they'll
be in New York on Monday.
It's hard to credit, isn't it?
I've robbed you of such a chance.
You've robbed me of nothing
I wouldn't gladly give.
What did Mr Barrow mean about
expecting a report?
Something and nothing.
Are you still awake?
I was on my way to bed and something
told me to put on my coat
and walk over and check on you.
I hope you don't...
How long have you been like this?
I really don't feel well at all.
Right. I'm going now to fetch
Doctor Clarkson...
No, it's too late. It's too late!
I'll be back as soon as I can.
No fuss. Please.
Try and drink. I'll send your maid up
with some tea and some more water.
How was dinner?
Uphill. I'm so bored with
Mr Blake's cold shoulder.
He hasn't warmed up, then?
According to Mr Napier,
he finds me aloof.
I'm not aloof, am I?
Do you want me to answer truthfully
or like a lady's maid?
Let's move on.
I heard you persuaded his lordship
to let Mr Bates stay here
and I'm so very grateful.
Then, you know Mrs Hughes
asked me to intervene...
..and told me why.
Yes. So she said.
We still can't find out who he was?
No.
He was a stranger, a...
I don't know, a robber, but after...
Afterwards, he just ran off.
But, if you described him?
And ought you to see
Doctor Clarkson,
just to make sure?
M'lady, I...
I don't mind your knowing.
In fact, I'm glad in a way that
there's honesty between us again but,
but I can't talk about it.
Even to me? Because I want to help.
You've helped me,
God knows, in the past,
and now I want to help you.
I can't talk about it, m'lady.
Not even to you.
That's it. I should be in bed.
Before you go, I'm worried about
Alfred coming back quite so soon.
I thought you liked the lad?
Oh, I do. Very much.
But, we've had such trouble
with Ivy and Daisy.
We don't want it stirred up again.
Can we put him off, just this once?
I don't think I've got his
parents' address, if I ever had it.
It's a shame.
- We're to end by mithering again.
- Oh!
She was a bit ill this morning,
but I thought it was just influenza.
This was never 'flu.
It looks like bronchitis.
But there is a lot of 'flu about and
my nurses are run off their feet.
I won't be able to spare...
I can do whatever needs to be done.
She'll need proper supervision,
otherwise there's a real danger it
could turn into pneumonia.
We'll have to hire someone...
No. I can manage.
There'll be no let up.
I know. What's the treatment?
Inhalants, really.
I'll bring some in the morning.
The main thing is to keep
her temperature down
and to stop pneumonia taking hold.
Morning, Ivy.
Oh, come on! I only asked
what a million men would ask.
And I only answered what
a million women would answer.
He's coming this tea time!
I'll meet him off the train,
give him a drink
and send him on his way.
It'll be too late to send him on
his way if he gets here after five!
Then I'll have to bite the bullet
and put him up at the pub.
Won't he find that peculiar?
I don't think so.
I'll tell him we're all very busy.
Say there's 'flu in the house and
he mustn't miss out on his course.
You're quite a plotter
when you want to be, aren't you?
It's a skill all women must learn.
But are you certain?
- There must be something we can do.
- There isn't.
I can manage easily with help
from the servants.
We just have to stop it
turning into pneumonia.
That's the real danger.
It seems rather unfair
to saddle you with it all.
Why should you do it and not us?
Because I'm a trained nurse.
Why is the food so disgusting,
suddenly?
She doesn't know what she's saying.
I wouldn't be too sure.
Everything she puts into my mouth
is absolutely disgusting.
Perhaps we'd better
get out of your way.
That's all I ask.
I'll ring up if there's any change.
- I'm disappointed, Mr Carson.
- You don't want the 'flu.
You can't risk missing any more of
the course when you started late.
That's true...
I've booked you a room at the pub.
And it's on the house.
You didn't need to do that.
I think I did.
You've missed the last train.
You're very kind, Mr Carson.
We'll have a drink first.
You and me, man to man.
And then, I'll leave you to it.
Why did Alfred change his plans?
Mrs Hughes won't know, will she?
That's rather disappointing.
What have you got to be
disappointed about?
It'd be nice to see him.
I don't know why.
Why not?
I'll tell you.
Because you made his life a misery
with your unkindness
and your cold and vicious heart.
Steady on, Daisy. I don't think
Ivy's quite deserved this.
Well, we know one thing....
You were right to put him off!
Tonight there can be no let up.
You mustn't sleep, you must not let
her temperature get higher.
I want another nurse! I insist!
This, this one talks too much!
She's like a drunken vicar!
The family took me in
and kept me close
when my link with them had gone.
I owe them a great deal.
If you insist.
I'll look in later.
Ring at the slightest change.
Well, the pigs have arrived.
Oh, I'd have come, if I'd known.
They said you'd gone
to your grandmother's.
It all went off smoothly.
We can see them tomorrow.
Did you get the message about
the tickets for the talk in Ripon?
I did. Why can't she come?
Because Mama's ill
and Isobel is nursing her.
What's the thing in Ripon?
A Liberal MP is speaking.
I don't think I'll bother.
Just because we're not political,
you mustn't be put off.
You won't come with me, then?
I'd rather go to the stake.
But what sort of errands?
Oh, you know. This and that.
Seeing friends, buying clothes,
errands.
I hope Sir John Bullock isn't one
of your "errands". He is not!
Oh, let her go, Aunt Rosamund.
All right, but you'll be back
in time for dinner.
I'm sure I will. You're a darling.
Taxi!
"I'm sure I will."
What does that mean?
I don't know
why Mama let her come.
Darling, please tell me
what's the matter.
You seem so preoccupee lately.
What do you mean you'll be 'out'
tomorrow night?
I'll be away,
but I don't want Mama to know.
It's not very difficult.
It is difficult for me.
To be put in a position of falsehood
where your parents are concerned.
You said yourself I'm a grown woman
and you're not a spy.
The last time you did this you were
with your Mr Gregson, weren't you?
So it can't be a repetition.
Oh, my dear.
My dear...
I'm so pleased to see you.
I keep thinking
you'll forget about me.
Rose!
I won't forget you. Ever.
But...
But, what?
Rose, I like you very much...
But?
What can we hope
to come out of this?
Can't we just
be in the moment?
I don't know many men like you and
you don't know many girls like me.
Ain't that the truth?
Then let's enjoy it!
You know what the French say?
Vive le difference!
Do you think Lord Grantham
will enjoy the 'difference'?
Or Lady Mary?
You're not scared of them, are you?
No.
Good.
Then you'll take me
to the club tonight.
But first... Kiss me.
Or don't you want to?
Oh, I want to.
Don't you worry about that.
I'm not even sure which
frightens me most...
What may have happened
to Michael or...the baby.
Erm...
What do you propose to do?
It's...
..hard to say the words but...
I've decided to get rid of it.
How terrible it is to hear that.
Please don't pretend
you won't be relieved when I do.
You're not being fair.
I will support you
whatever you decide,
just as Cora will and Robert.
That sounds like a speech from
The Second Mrs Tanqueray.
But, you don't mean a word of it.
I do.
So, I'd be welcome in your
drawing room, would I?
"Have you met my niece
and her charming bastard?"
I refuse to be shocked!
But, what will you say when
Mr Gregson walks through the door,
with a full explanation
for his silence?
Nothing.
I pray he is alive,
but, if he is, I won't say a thing.
And you will marry him?
If he still wants me to.
So, your whole life
will be based on a lie?
Have you thought about that?
I am killing the wanted child
of a man I'm in love with
and you ask me if
I've thought about it?
I assume you'll be
away for the night
because you have booked into some...
..some place where
they will do this?
How did you find it?
There was a magazine in the ladies'
waiting room at King's Cross.
You do realise it is quite illegal?
Of course.
And dangerous!
What will I say to your parents
if it goes wrong?
You'll think of something.
Very well.
If you've made up your mind...
..I shall come with you.
Where's Evelyn?
Dining with friends of his parents.
He telephoned earlier, and Tom's
gone off to a political meeting,
so I'm afraid it's just us.
Don't be afraid.
But, we are afraid!
How can brainless dullards like us
ever hope to entertain Mr Blake?
Mary?! That sounded a little rude.
I can take it. Did the pigs arrive?
Absolutely.
Although un-witnessed by me.
I'll go with Tom tomorrow.
Well, I'm curious to see them
and I'll be out all day.
Why don't we walk down after dinner?
Lady Grantham?
You two go. I'll take it on trust.
Well, it's a nice evening.
What about it?
Well, it's quite a long walk,
but I don't mind,
if you really want to.
Is this seat taken?
I was keeping it for a friend.
Good evening ladies and gentlemen.
I'm John Ward.
In a while I'll ask for questions
so please remember
what made you indignant
when you last read a newspaper.
Are you trying to attract my
attention ahead of the rest, madam?
I just wanted him
to take this chair.
Do you know this gentleman?
No.
You just wanted to sit next to him?
Er no, it was because he asked.
He asked to sit next to you?
Ladies and gentlemen, we've been
made privy to a very romantic story.
Why don't I sit down?
Of course, the question uppermost
in all of your minds is,
why the split between Mr Asquith
and Mr Lloyd George?
Because a divided party
spells electoral defeat.
Well, can I say this?
It doesn't have to.
He's wrong there.
Since 1910....
But you support them?
Not really.
I'm a Socialist. Or I was.
And in 1915...
What happened to your friend?
I don't know.
It just seemed silly
to keep the chair empty.
I'm glad.
Sssh!
Of course,
history teaches us that in 1910...
The idea is to learn from these,
then, if it's going well, expand.
And you have a good pig man?
He comes highly recommended.
Well, that's important because...
What is it?
What is it? What's happening?
This one's almost dead.
Why?
It looks dehydrated.
It's had no water.
Isn't there a water trough?
They've kicked it over.
How could this have happened?
All too easily.
Should I fetch the pig man?
I could run back to the house?
If only we'd brought a car!
There's no time.
Where's the nearest clean water?
There's a water pipe, in the barn.
Should we drive the animals to it?
When they've had no water this long
you must give it to them gradually.
Wait a moment.
Oh!
I'm sorry about that earlier.
You can't blame him
for having a bit of fun.
There won't be much fun for them
after the election.
What do you care,
if you're a Socialist?
I'm not sure what I am,
except a man in search
of a better world.
Why did you leave Ireland?
Sometimes I ask myself that.
Will you go back?
No.
Why not?
It's a long story.
I'd better go.
Thanks for the seat. Goodnight.
Does no-one care
whether I live or die?
There, there.
This will make you feel better.
Hmm?
Compared to what?
Oh!
I'm fine.
I'm fine!
Suit yourself.
I'm off. Erm...
Well done, for containing
the Downton heart-breaker.
Everyone's gone to bed,
but Lady Mary's still out
with Mr Blake.
What should I do about locking up?
I wonder what's taking the time.
Nothing.
Well, nothing like that.
I should leave the front door open
with the key in the lock.
They can turn it when they come in.
You're not frightened of burglars?
Mr Carson, this is England.
Hmph.
Are they going to be all right?
I think so.
I'll watch them for another hour
and give them one more drink.
But you, you should go.
I'm not going! They're my pigs.
Oh.
Here, take my coat.
At least it's dry.
Not quite the evening we planned.
Oh.
What do I look like?
You belong in Country Life.
"Lady Mary Crawley,
"seen here to advantage relaxing
at the family seat in Yorkshire."
Ha, ha.
Oh!
Where have you been?
Having such a dreamy time.
Is she furious that I missed dinner?
Why can't you just fit in for once?
Shall I go and make my peace.
Good night, Rose.
Who'd have thought it?
I can scramble eggs,
but that's about it.
I suspect Carson had plans for this,
but too bad.
I don't deserve such attention.
You certainly do.
You've completely saved our bacon.
Literally!
So, you're a practical farmer,
as well as a theoretician.
Not sure I was expecting that.
I didn't expect to see you
as a cook and a water carrier.
A night of discovery.
Good discoveries. For me, anyway.
I love how they've all gone to bed,
without the slightest
concern about us.
What did they think we were doing?
We went for a walk and vanished.
Who knows what they thought?
I'm ever so sorry, m'lady.
Please, don't apologise...
Ivy, m'lady.
Ivy.
Well, if you're getting up,
it's time for us to go to bed.
Would you please tell Anna
I'll ring when I'm awake?
Good night.
- Thank you.
- Ma'am.
It's right.
This is it.
It doesn't look very right.
It should say Thompson on the bell.
Well, here goes.
If you'll wait, the doctor will be
with you very soon.
As long as he is a doctor.
You don't have to stay.
Of course I do.
Would you like a glass of water?
No, thank you.
It's not that I don't love him,
you know.
I do love him...
..and I would have loved his baby.
But, I just...
..can't see over the top of this.
No.
I don't want to be an outcast.
I don't want to be some funny woman
living in Maida Vale
people never talk about.
Sybil might have brought it off,
but not me.
Oh no, I see that.
But, you think I'm terribly selfish.
Please don't put words into my mouth.
I don't know what I think,
except that I wish it were over.
I can't go back to the nursery.
Not with Mary's son and Sybil's
daughter waiting there.
I can't do that.
I won't be able to do that.
Not for a while.
Not for ever, I don't think.
The doctor's just...
I'm afraid this is a mistake.
There's no reason...
I'm sorry to waste your time but...
This is a mistake.
It seems it was a mistake.
Why?! Why has everything changed?
I've arranged things for tonight!
Then un-arrange them.
Why should I?
Because I'm telling you to.
Just do it, dear.
Are you going to tell Cora?
I suppose I must do, at some stage.
If you want me to be there,
let me know.
I'm certain there's a way forward.
Certain of it.
Well, the decision's been made now.
- You've heard about our adventures?
- I'm very impressed.
- There you are!
- I'm afraid I slept late.
Have you remembered
Tony Gillingham's coming tonight?
What? Why?
He's driving up to fish the Spey.
He asked if he could stay the night.
I'm sure I told you.
Did he used to be Tony Foyle?
That's right. Why?
We served together in the war
on the Iron Duke with Jellicoe.
Were you at Jutland?
We were.
Well, you'll see him again tonight.
I tried to put him off, but he
didn't seem to want to be put off.
Don't worry. It's perfectly fine.
I gather you were the heroine
of the pig drama.
So, I'm not aloof now?
Not a bit.
Mucking in with the best of them.
Only trouble for me is...
I'm afraid it's increased
the competition.
Hello, Daisy. Hello, Ivy.
We thought you weren't coming.
Mr Carson warned me about the 'flu.
What 'flu?
Mrs Patmore and I both think we're
coming down with the 'flu, don't we?
We do, indeed, and we're wanting to
spare Alfred from it if we could.
You look well enough to me.
Looks can be deceptive.
We're so pleased to see you.
Aren't we? Daisy? Jimmy?
We've missed you.
I don't know about that.
Have you really missed me, Ivy?
Oh, I have.
The place isn't the same
without you, is it, Daisy?
If I thought you meant that,
I'm not sure I could go.
Which makes it sadder you have to.
You're right. I can't stay long.
I've got to get back to London.
I should have come last night.
Mr Carson was being over careful.
Yes, I'm sure that's what it was.
Alfred? What are you doing here?
He, he thought he'd look in,
before he catches the train.
We've warned him about our 'flu!
So, we got all the trouble and a bill
to pay at the pub to pay, too!
Oh, go on with you. I'm sure you
don't grudge him a decent dinner.
But I do grudge him
the tears and heartbreak
that'll flavour my puddings
for weeks to come!
Well, you've given me summat
to think about, Ivy, and I will.
That's such good news,
if you really are hungry.
Well, I'm, I'm not ravenous,
but I wouldn't mind
a piece of toast.
I'll ask straight away.
Can't you ring...?
Well, really, really.
Doctor Clarkson, when you go,
would you please take
that mad woman with you?
That mad woman
has refused to leave your side
for the last two days and two nights
and she has not slept nor eaten
since you were taken ill.
But, there were nurses here?
I remember a nurse wiping my brow.
She was that nurse, Lady Grantham.
But, what about Cora and Mary?
They offered,
but Mrs Crawley felt she had
more knowledge than they.
I suppose that has a ring of truth.
I've asked them to bring up
some toast and tea.
Now Lady Grantham's a little better,
it's time you had a break.
I might go home and have a bath.
Shall I come back later?
Oh yes... Yes, dear.
That would be very kind.
Good.
I can stay all evening.
Perhaps we can play cards.
Oh...
You will be rewarded in Heaven.
The sooner the better.
I think this is the right place.
Well, if it isn't Mr Gillingham!
Welcome back!
Pull up a chair and sit down.
I suppose you've come
to shake us up again.
Will there be any more
Racing Demon this time?
Depends if you're up to it, but I
expect you've all got things to do.
Miss Baxter, I wondered if you...
If I could what?
If you could let me have
some white thread.
I seem to have run out.
Of course.
Go on then.
What've you been up to
since we saw you last?
Having fun and games at other
people's expense?
I'd better not tell you too much.
I don't want to shock the ladies.
I hope you don't mind
my turning up again.
It's the perfect stopping point
between London and Inverness.
I don't mind at all. How are you?
Well, missing you, mainly.
Sounds to me
as if the needle's got stuck.
How's Mabel?
I gather Charles Blake's here.
Of course, you served together.
We don't really know him,
but he and Evelyn Napier are
writing a report for the Government.
He'll be up here for a few weeks.
Lucky devil.
Don't get to like him
better than me.
No chance of that.
They're out all day,
and even in the evenings
we've hardly spoken until yesterday.
Erm, what happened yesterday?
Some pigs arrived and of course,
as usual, Mr Blake was...
Anyway, what does it matter?
Hello, Charles.
It's good to see you again.
This is nice.
What task brings you to Yorkshire?
Nothing as meaningful as yours.
What report are you working on?
Current health of the landed estate.
My usual stamping ground.
So, did you get everything done?
Why do you ask?
No reason.
By the time we got back, we looked
as if we'd been wrestling in mud.
- And had you?
- No!
But then, it's always nice to leave
something for another time.
So, what are the chances for Downton?
I'd say they look bright.
Lady Mary and the family mean to
give it everything they've got.
If Mary means to give it
everything she's got,
then that is a very
considerable gift.
I couldn't agree more.
Dinner everyone.
They said you were in here.
What can I do for you, Mrs Hughes?
Nothing. You can do nothing for me.
Because I know who you are
and I know what you've done.
And while you're here,
if you value your life,
I should stop playing the joker
and keep to the shadows.
I'm afraid we were a bit drunk
that night, Anna and I,
so you're right,
we were both to blame.
No, Mr Green.
YOU were to blame and ONLY you.
Does Mr Bates know?
Not that it was you.
Thank you.
Don't you dare thank me!
I've not kept silent for your sake.
I think it's Gin.
Oh, so it is.
I'd forgotten
what a good game this is.
Yes. I'd forgotten.
How long does it go on for?
Oh, ages!
Oh, goody, goody.
Oh, dear. Alfred's relit the taper.
Well, to be young is to have
your heart broken,
in the kitchens at Downton,
like everywhere else.
I've spent half the day brushing
the mud out of his dinner jacket.
Why can't he have his own valet
instead of making work for me?
Anna?
Sorry. Yes. What were you saying?
Mr Blake's evening shoes were
quite a challenge, I can tell you.
I wasn't working here then.
It's a pity. I admire Nellie Melba.
I'd have loved to hear her sing.
You must be joking.
Why? I thought she had
a beautiful voice.
Screaming and screeching, as if her
finger was caught in the door?
I couldn't take it
for one more moment.
So, what did you do?
Well, I came down here for a bit
of peace and quiet, that's what.
Is that more
of the cauliflower cheese?
This morning in Thirsk,
I saw Rose meeting a man.
I'm frightened when Mr Green
and Mr Bates are in the same room.
I think I know how
I can keep the baby.
There's a family who's been at
Downton for years. Very reckless.
You'd never do anything foolish?
Certainly not.
Rosamund told me.
What did she say?
Only that you needed a little
cherishing, that's all.
His lordship's back!
What a relief to be able
to drink in public!
You never had a drink
all the time you were there?
I won't keep it a secret!
All I want is for you
not to lose control of your life.